So you want CH GPT and CLO to have
infinite memory that is 100% local and
private. Well, thanks to this MCP, this
is now possible. It's called MEM agent
and it takes the concept of context
engineering to the next level. But the
crazy thing is this project is basically
unknown. So here is what MEM agent can
do. It can give infinite local memory
for all of your AI agents. And not only
that, it can actually connect that
memory between CHGBT, cloud, Google
Docs, LM Studio and multiple other apps.
So you can reuse the same context across
all the tools that you use. Now to
really understand how this works, you
have to understand these two parts.
First, the model itself. So MEM agent is
a 4 billion parameter LLM specifically
fine-tuned to be an expert at memory
management, retrieval, storing of
context, and organizing markdown files.
The second part is the MCP aka the
server. This is what wraps the MEM agent
and exposes its capabilities to other
applications like cloud code, like CHBD,
like Google Docs or GitHub. So all of
your data is stored locally, which not
only keeps all of your data completely
private, but also you won't get the risk
of Claude reporting you to the police.
And no, this isn't a joke. When Clause 4
came out, there were multiple instances
of it trying to contact the authorities
where people were sending inappropriate
or illegal pronouns. And in the future,
I wouldn't be surprised if the big AI
companies actually implement something
like this. So, it will be more and more
important to keep all of your
information local and private. Now,
normally you would need a very good
computer to run models locally, right?
For example, the 12b GPD OSS model
requires you to have like 70 80 GB of
RAM, which most people don't have. But
luckily, this is just a 4B model. So,
basically, unless you have a 20-year-old
laptop, anybody can run this. And the
best part is look how well it performs
on the knowledge benchmarks. It is
almost as good as Quenfrey 235B which is
literally 60 times bigger. But there is
a small issue. There is literally no
content and no tutorials on this.
Running this without any tutorials was
very difficult. So, I've gathered all of
the lessons, all of the errors, all the
mistakes I made and compress them into
the single video so that when you finish
watching this, you will have MEM agent
running locally on your computer, and
you can begin storing all of your files,
documents, and knowledge completely
locally and privately while still being
able to use them inside of the best AI
tools like CH GPD and cloth. So, if
you're serious about AI and data
privacy, make sure to watch until the
end. So, the first thing you have to do
is clone the GitHub repository. Now,
this is much simpler than it sounds. If
you've never done this, don't be scared.
You don't need to be a professional
developer to get it up and running. Just
follow what I'm doing. I'm going to
leave a link to the GitHub below the
video. So, click on code and copy this
link right here. Boom. Then switch to
your code editor of choice. Could be
cursor, VS Code, Windsurf, doesn't
matter. Open up the terminal and type in
git clone and paste in the link. Boom.
On the right, we should see a new folder
me agent MCP with all of the files
listed inside. Then let's type clear to
empty the terminal and type in cd me and
then press tab. Boom. Me agent MCP. And
now we're in the folder right here. And
by the way, a pro tip. I would recommend
you choose a directory on your computer
that doesn't have any spaces in the
names of the folders. Otherwise, this
will cause issues later on. So just go
to documents and create a folder with no
spaces. Now this project comes with
what's called a make file, which
includes a lot of commands bundled up
together into shortcuts. So we can use
this to actually speedrun the
installation and not understand all of
these complex commands because uh the
creators of this project made it a lot
simpler for us. So let me expand the
terminal and let's start with make
check- UV. This will check whether you
have UV installed on your machine and
this is a package manager that's a lot
faster than pip. So let's type clear
again. And the next command we need to
run is make install. This will install
lm studio. This is an application that
allows you to run AI models locally. So,
some of you might already know LM Studio
with the UI version, right? Where you
can chat with the models in a similar
style as you can chat with models in
CHIGBT. But this installs the CLI, the
command line interface of LM Studio,
which works exactly the same, but you
can use it to build projects and
applications without having all of the
graphical user interface, which can slow
things down. So, as you can see, I
already have LM Studio installed, but if
you don't, this command make install
will install it and set it up exactly as
you need. Now, the next step is to
actually run the agent itself. But real
quick, if you want to become an AI first
developer, then make sure to join the
new society. Inside of the classroom, we
have lots of exclusive highle content
from how to code with AI to how to build
your own AI SAS. For example, here we
have the ultimate codex guide that
teaches you everything you need to know
about OpenAI Codex. We also have modules
on cloth code and cursor. And with each
module, you get exclusive resources such
as my settings.json or my cloth MD, my
context engineering, my sub agents, my
custom commands, everything you need to
know to be an AI first developer. Plus,
if you go with the annual plan, you'll
get a one-on-one call with me where you
can ask me anything and you'll get a
year of Vectoral Pro for free. On top of
all that, we do two weekly calls every
single week. So if you really lock in
for 12 months, you will become a top 1%
AI first developer even if you are a
complete beginner today. So click the
first link below the video and join
today. I'll see you inside. Now back to
me agent. The next step is to actually
run the agent which also includes
installing the 4 billion model locally.
So again type make run- agent enter. Now
me agent comes with three different
models and this depends how powerful
your computer is. four bit quantized, 8
bit and 16. And to keep it super simple,
this is the fastest one and this is the
most powerful one. And 8 bit is the
balanced option, right? So depending on
how powerful your computer is. If you
have like a M3 or M4 MacBook, you can
probably run the BF-16. If you have like
a mid-tier GPU, you can probably do the
8 bit one. If you want the fastest
inference and you're not sure, just go
with the 4bit and then just type the
number of the model that you choose and
hit enter. Then it searches if the model
is already installed. And here there
were no matches found. So it's going to
ask you to install a model from hugging
face. Now if you don't know what hugging
face is, this is basically like the
GitHub but for AI models. Here you can
find all kinds of LLMs, data sets, and
anything AI related basically. And since
MEM agent is a fine-tuned version of
this open source model, Quenfrey 4B
thinking 257, you can go here and see
like all the files, you can download the
weights, you can inspect it if you want.
Yeah, open source models. So, it's a lot
more transparent than these big models
from these closed source companies.
Anyways, let's go back into our setup
and let's just hit enter again. You
don't have to understand how hugging
face works because this setup makes it
really easy. So, hit enter again. And
the 4-bit version is just 2.28 GB, which
is not big at all. And there we go. Once
it finishes installing, it says server
is now running on port 8000. Do not
close this terminal because the model is
now loaded which is essential for apps
like claw desktop to be able to use the
model through the MCP. Now if you ran
into any errors during the make install
part of the setup, you might need to run
this command right here. And what this
does is basically it adds the LM Studio
CLI into your path. So if you're seeing
the error LMS command not found, this
should fix it. Okay, so the next step is
choosing the folder where we want our
local memory to be stored. So I actually
recommend creating a new folder for
this. Something like local memory. Boom.
And this is where me agent will store
all of the markdown files. And you can
actually edit them yourself as well. Now
later in the video, I'll show you how
you can use cursor to actually do the
context engineering yourself together
with the ME agent. So sometimes you just
want to write stuff yourself and with
cursor you can do that a lot faster.
Anyways, we have the MEM agent running
in this terminal. So, I recommend you
creating a new one. And the first thing
you have to do is again CD into the MEM
agent MCP folder. So, hit enter and then
type in make
setup. This will run a Python script
that will want you to select a folder
which will serve as the main memory
directory where all of the MD files will
be stored. So, we create this local
memory folder. So, just click on choose
and there we go. Memory path saved to
that memory path. users daily documents
MEM agent root local memory. All right.
So once you run the MEM agent locally,
you have to check the model name. Right?
This is very important. Here you have
the identifier M me agent LX2.
Whatever you see as the identifier
basically copy that go to the right.
Find the MLX model name and rename this
to this. This needs to be matching the
identifier. If you don't do that, you'll
run into a lot of errors. But since
you're watching this video, you won't
run into those issues. So, make sure to
subscribe if you want to see more of
these cutting edge super small projects.
I'm telling you, nobody's talking about
this. Nobody even knows this exists. So,
if you want me to make more videos on
these cutting edge underground AI
projects, make sure to hit subscribe. Uh
it takes 2 seconds and it's completely
free. So, the next thing you should
check is actually if you run multiple
instances. So, again, let me cd into
mamm h folder. And to check that, you
should do lmssp. This will show all of
the instances you're running. And as you
can see, I made the mistake of running
multiple instances. And this is
obviously just wasting resources. So I'm
going to do lms unload me- agent-mlx.
Okay, because we're not using this one.
Remember, we using the colon 2. So we
can unload this one. That way if I run
the same command lps,
we see that only one model, one agent is
loaded. All right, let's clear. Next, we
need to generate the MCP JSON. So, type
in make generate-mc-json.
And this will create a new file named
MCP.json right here. And this is
actually needed for us to copy into the
MCP. So, we can use it like in cloud
code, in cursor, uh JGBD connector,
whatever is using MCPS, you know,
GitHub, you can use MEM agent with that
software. And for that connection, you
need to actually integrate this JSON
into the JSON of the tool you're going
to be using. So I'm going to show you
how to set this up with CL desktop where
you can be using Opus 4.1, you know, one
of the best models in the world with all
of your local private memory that is
guarded by the ME agent. So that cloth
only gets the stuff that it really needs
and all of your private stuff, all all
the secret sensitive stuff, right? All
of the conspiracy theories you're
researching that the government
shouldn't know about, all that stuff
stays locally on your machine. So, go to
claw.ai/d download and select the
operating system you have and simply
download the installer for cloud
desktop. Once you do that, simply type
in cloud to launch the app. Now, if
you're doing this for the first time,
you'll need to log in with the same
enthropic account you use for cloud code
or for claw.ai in the browser. If you
don't have an enthropic account, first
of all, why? Second of all, it takes 30
seconds, so just create one. Anyways,
inside of Cloud Code, open up the
sidebar. Go to the bottom, click on your
user, and click on settings. Then we can
close the sidebar. Go to the bottom. At
the bottom, you'll find developer. And
here you can edit your MCP server
config. So click on edit config. It will
open up this file right here, cloth
desktop config.json. So what you need to
do is you need to open this in any text
editor, code editor, doesn't matter. And
then we can actually use cursor or cloud
code or codex any AI tool to help us
edit the JSON. If you've never used any
MCPS this will be empty. So it will
actually bit easier for you because you
can literally just copy paste the MCP
JSON in the cloth desktop config. But if
you already have MCP servers like me,
you can see I have the veil MCP which by
the way a lot of people still don't know
that Vectal has MCP. So if you don't use
it, you're missing out. But anyways,
what we need to do is we need to copy
the MCP.json and simply say update cloud
boom desktop config by adding this new
MCP at the bottom.
Boom. Enter. And we can use cursor or
any AI coding editor to help us adjust
this file to properly add this in the
correct format. Now, actually here comes
a caveat because this is the recommended
setup from ME agent, right? And as I
said, there is not much info about this
project on the web. And I was running
into some serious issues with this
setup. So, actually, I'm going to tweak
it a bit. And this is what I figured out
after like well over an hour of
debugging is um a different way to
phrase the MCP. So, instead of doing a
bash, we're going to use UV and we're
going to run it in a more clean way. So,
I'm going to say update the schema of
this second MCP to follow the setup from
the screenshot. Just make sure to keep
the directory
as this. And I'm going to copy the
directory of our folder, which is just,
you know, the directory at the start you
chose. As I told you, keep something,
keep it simple. Don't choose something
with spaces in its name. So I'm I'm just
going to instruct it to keep the same
directory with this new setup where we
use UV as the command and we structure
the arguments in a different way because
this way didn't work for me. So maybe it
works for you. But hey, so this is the
way and feel free to pause the video and
just copy it or screenshot it. But this
setup works for me. So that's what I'm
showing you. So anyways, what we need to
do is now we need to close claw desktop.
So let's close this completely. Shut it
down. Then open up the terminal again.
We need to open a new terminal again. CD
into MEM agent MCP folder. Can actually
collapse the chat. We don't need it. And
then we need to start the MCP server. So
we should have the agent still loaded.
There we go. Our agent is still loaded.
You can check it with LMSPS.
But we don't have the MCP server
running. So type in uv run python. And
then we need to get into this location
to get the server. py. So literally type
in the name of the folder mcp
server slash
server. py enter. And this will start
the actual mcp server that cloth code
can access to use agent. So this took
like 2 seconds but here's what it should
look like. It's using fast mcbp 2.0. And
yeah now we should be ready to use it.
So again let's start clo desktop from
the scratch. And I'm getting an error
about the vector MCB because I changed
the uh API key. So you guys don't use my
vector account and don't complete my
tasks for me. But anyways, what I want
to see is if the MEM agent one works and
the best way to do that is to simply
ask. So I can say use the MEM agent to
save the information that I'm currently
recording a video for YouTube. So
obviously since this is our first time
using it, we don't have any info stored.
So we need to use the MEM agent to save
some info which we should see by the way
in our local memory appear right here.
So on the right in our file folder we
have the ME agent MCP. This is all the
files for this project obviously but
then we have this local memory and there
we go. We have the user MD file which is
the main markdown file with information
about the user which is me in this case
and you can see me agent saved this in a
nice context engineering way. user
information current activity recording
YouTube video for AI content current
projects YouTube video so let's switch
back to claw desktop and we can see done
I've saved that you're currently
recording YouTube video now this is
obviously level one we can go way deeper
the concept you have to understand about
me agent is the concept of entities this
is how you store information about
different areas or different people in
your life so you can say like store the
information that I have three cats in
Czech Republic use me agent to create a
new entity for Yes. Boom. There we go.
And now this should hopefully create a
new MD file as an entity. So let me put
it to the side so we can see on the top
right we see our local memory folder and
the user MD is the main file where
everything is linked via wiki links. So
there you go a new subfolder appeared
entities and you can see it's named
check cats and we can see info about my
cats in Czech Republic. And then the
boom user MD got updated with user
information being extended with pets.
And then this is a wiki link to that MD
file. So this is how you build a fully
local database and knowledge base of
everything about you. And again the
beauty is that you can use this by
yourself as well. You don't have to run
through the you know claw desktop or
through any middleman to use the me
agent to save info. You can simply edit
it yourself. So let's say I want to add
a new entity, new file. I want to add my
company.m MD.
I can say David's company industry
task management and productivity name
vectal.ai. You can add MR. So currently
we're at almost 11K and whatever else
you want. So you can build your context
files. And you probably already have
some files if you're using Obsidian,
maybe you're using Google Docs or
notion, maybe you have your knowledge
somewhere already and you want to use it
with the best AI models in the world
such as cloth for Opus, which you can
use right here instead of CL code, but
you don't want to give it all the info,
right? So then you use MEM agent to only
load the relevant info. Now, you might
be thinking, okay, David, but how do I
protect certain types of information,
right? Maybe I don't want to reveal my
MR or I don't want to reveal location of
my cats, whatever. Right? There is a
feature inside of me agent called
filters. So again, let's open up a
terminal. Can create a new one and type
in CD. Again, we need a CD into the ME
agent folder. And now let's type in make
add filters. And this gives you the
option to type in what you never want to
be revealed, such as do not ever reveal
the revenue of my companies. Enter. And
then you can type in quit quit with the
parenthesis like this to end the process
of adding filters. Now if we look into
the right of our folder, we should find
a new file filters. And this includes
all of the filters. So you can just add
them manually. It's faster than you know
type and make add filters. And now if I
go into cloud and I create a new chat,
let's say let's use open right here. New
chat. I can say use me agent to tell me
everything you know about me and my
companies. So it should tell me
everything except for the revenue. So
let's see if the filters work correctly.
I'll use the memory agent to retrieve
information about you and your
companies. Boom. You can see that this
is the question going to the MEM agent.
Right now it's reasoning about the
output of the MEM agent. And let's see
if it fails the test or if it passes the
test. Okay. So let's see based on the
memories agent search. Here's what I
know about you. Personal information
connect.
Okay. You have free cats recording
YouTube video. your companies.
Currently, there's no company
information. So, you can see me agent
was actually even more strict than it
needed to be and it didn't reveal
anything about the companies. So, then
obviously what you could do is go into
filters and fine-tune your instructions
so that you're you can say like you can
reveal basic info about companies like
names, a website, you know, whatever
industry, but you cannot reveal the
revenue to clarify how it should
protect. But you can see that it's very
good at protecting whatever we put into
the filters, right? So, I put do not
ever reveal the revenue of my companies
and was very careful not to reveal any
of that information, but it did reveal
that I'm recording a video about the
CADS stuff that I didn't protect with
the filters. So, MCP agent is the way
something like this, maybe this project
will be successful, maybe it won't be
successful, who knows? But something
like this is a taste of the future. This
is what context engineering will look
like where all of your files will be
securely stored locally especially the
private sensitive info and then when you
want to use cutting edge models like
Opus 4.1 you will have a locally running
agent fetching that info and only giving
the stuff that cloth or CHBT actually
needs nothing more nothing less
protecting the private filtered info
from ever accessing the internet okay so
this is the reason why it didn't reveal
any info about my companies is because I
didn't create a wiki link. So what I
should do, I should do company and do my
company here. And now it will know for
user.md that I do own a company and
where it can find more info about that
company. So anytime you create a file
manually, just make sure to create the
wiki link as well. And again, if you use
cursor, it will just prefill that for
you like it did for me right now. So
that's the beauty of that. And also
since this is different markdown files,
you can literally have an infinitely
long knowledge base. And that since MEM
agent is fine-tuned on knowledge
retrieval and working with MD files, you
only load into cloth and into chat GBT
the things that you actually need to
load. So you don't hit your limits
whereas otherwise you would need to
paste in a long book if you properly
structure it through me agent into
different MD files. only the most
relevant contacts get loaded and you can
use you can either pay for a cheaper
plan maybe you don't need to pay for
$200 month plan on cloth and $200 month
plan on JGBT like I'm doing maybe you
just have the $20 plan on both of these
and then have your files nicely
structured locally in MD files with me
agent fetching the relevant info as it
needs to be used. Now as I said earlier
this can be used with many different
softwares. So in the folder actually
that comes from the GitHub repo, you can
see this memory connectors uh subfolder
where we have setups for a lot of
different things such as chat GPD. So
you can export your chat GPD history or
if you want a live connector, there is a
file for that as well. Then we have
GitHub live. You can use GitHub to chat
with repositories through the API and
get different issues, get file names,
stuff like that. Load that into cloud
desktop, load that into cursor, any tool
that uses MCPS. You can also do Google
Docs. So a lot of us use Google Docs for
storing of our documents and our files.
You can chat with Google Docs as well.
You can extract data through the Google
Drive API and feed that through web
agent into any tool you want. Same with
notion or nucleo and I wouldn't be
surprised if in a few weeks we see a lot
more different tools here. Maybe even
I'll add one for vexal. That would be
cool. But yeah, if you want to use chbpt
or github or Google docs, just explore
these files in here. And again, if you
use cursor or cloth code, you can just
ask them how does the chat GPT history
connector work and it will tell you how
it works, how to set it up and fix any
errors because this is a very new
project. So keep in mind there might be
stuff, you know, there might be errors
that are unexpected. Just use an AI tool
like cloth code, code codex or cursor to
work with these. And if you actually
want to become an expert at using cursor
cloth code codex, the perfect place to
do that is the new society. In the
classroom, we have everything you need
to know to become a top 1% AI developer.
Whether it is how to build your first AI
agents, whether it's all the templates
and presets from my past videos such as
pre-built automations, my AI agents, all
of my prompts and instructions right
here. And when I say all, I do mean all
of my prompts and instructions. Or if
you just want to learn how to use these
tools, right? how to use codex cloth
code or cursor like a top 1% of users
because I spent hundreds of hours with
these tools, well over 1,000 hours at
this point and I distilled all of the
best latest information into these
modules for you to learn. And again, if
you get the annual plan, you'll get a
one-on-one consulting call with me where
you can ask me literally anything. I
mean, I can help you integrate AI into
your business. I can help you get set
up, whatever you want to ask me. Plus,
another bonus you get if you get the
annual new society plan is a year of
Vectoral Pro completely for free. And
honestly, if you don't become successful
in those 12 months, I'll happily give
you your money back because I'm very
confident that all the content we have,
all of the weekly calls we have, all the
support with the great community is
going to turn you into an AI first
developer that has no problem building a
SAS or getting clients or making money
with AI. So, if you join and you see
like, hey, this is not for me. You know,
it's not really what I expected. I don't
like it. No worries. I'll personally
give you the money back, no questions
asked. The link to New Society is going
to be below the video. And with that
being said, thank you guys for watching.
Hopefully you enjoy this video on me
agent and I wish you a wonderful
productive week. See youa.